[
  {
    "question_no.": 1,
    "Question": "What is the outermost layer of the Earth?",
    "Option1": "Mantle",
    "Option2": "Core",
    "Option3": "Crust",
    "Option4": "Atmosphere",
    "Answer": "Crust"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 2,
    "Question": "What type of rock is formed from the cooling and solidification of molten magma or lava?",
    "Option1": "Sedimentary",
    "Option2": "Metamorphic",
    "Option3": "Igneous",
    "Option4": "Limestone",
    "Answer": "Igneous"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 3,
    "Question": "What is the process by which rocks are broken down into smaller pieces by physical or chemical means?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Deposition",
    "Option3": "Weathering",
    "Option4": "Compaction",
    "Answer": "Weathering"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 4,
    "Question": "What is the name of the supercontinent that existed approximately 300 million years ago?",
    "Option1": "Gondwana",
    "Option2": "Laurasia",
    "Option3": "Pangaea",
    "Option4": "Rodinia",
    "Answer": "Pangaea"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 5,
    "Question": "What is the primary gas that makes up the Earth's atmosphere?",
    "Option1": "Oxygen",
    "Option2": "Carbon Dioxide",
    "Option3": "Nitrogen",
    "Option4": "Argon",
    "Answer": "Nitrogen"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 6,
    "Question": "What is the name of the invisible line that divides the Earth into the Northern and Southern Hemispheres?",
    "Option1": "Prime Meridian",
    "Option2": "Equator",
    "Option3": "Tropic of Cancer",
    "Option4": "Arctic Circle",
    "Answer": "Equator"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 7,
    "Question": "What is the term for the shaking of the Earth's surface caused by the sudden release of energy in the Earth's crust?",
    "Option1": "Volcanic eruption",
    "Option2": "Landslide",
    "Option3": "Earthquake",
    "Option4": "Tsunami",
    "Answer": "Earthquake"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 8,
    "Question": "What is the name of the hot, molten rock that flows from a volcano?",
    "Option1": "Magma",
    "Option2": "Ash",
    "Option3": "Lava",
    "Option4": "Pumice",
    "Answer": "Lava"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 9,
    "Question": "What is the process by which water, wind, or ice moves weathered rock and soil particles?",
    "Option1": "Weathering",
    "Option2": "Deposition",
    "Option3": "Erosion",
    "Option4": "Compaction",
    "Answer": "Erosion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 10,
    "Question": "What is the deepest part of the ocean?",
    "Option1": "Mariana Trench",
    "Option2": "Puerto Rico Trench",
    "Option3": "Java Trench",
    "Option4": "Kermadec Trench",
    "Answer": "Mariana Trench"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 11,
    "Question": "What is the largest ocean on Earth?",
    "Option1": "Atlantic Ocean",
    "Option2": "Indian Ocean",
    "Option3": "Pacific Ocean",
    "Option4": "Arctic Ocean",
    "Answer": "Pacific Ocean"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 12,
    "Question": "What is the name of the layer of the atmosphere where weather phenomena occur?",
    "Option1": "Stratosphere",
    "Option2": "Mesosphere",
    "Option3": "Troposphere",
    "Option4": "Thermosphere",
    "Answer": "Troposphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 13,
    "Question": "What type of cloud is associated with thunderstorms?",
    "Option1": "Cirrus",
    "Option2": "Stratus",
    "Option3": "Cumulonimbus",
    "Option4": "Altocumulus",
    "Answer": "Cumulonimbus"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 14,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's physical structure and substance, its history, and the processes that act on it?",
    "Option1": "Meteorology",
    "Option2": "Oceanography",
    "Option3": "Geology",
    "Option4": "Ecology",
    "Answer": "Geology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 15,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process by which water vapor in the atmosphere turns into liquid water, forming clouds?",
    "Option1": "Evaporation",
    "Option2": "Precipitation",
    "Option3": "Condensation",
    "Option4": "Transpiration",
    "Answer": "Condensation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 16,
    "Question": "What is the main cause of the Earth's seasons?",
    "Option1": "Distance from the Sun",
    "Option2": "Earth's rotation",
    "Option3": "Tilt of Earth's axis",
    "Option4": "Solar flares",
    "Answer": "Tilt of Earth's axis"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 17,
    "Question": "What is the name of the Earth's magnetic field, which protects us from solar radiation?",
    "Option1": "Gravity",
    "Option2": "Ionosphere",
    "Option3": "Magnetosphere",
    "Option4": "Ozone layer",
    "Answer": "Magnetosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 18,
    "Question": "What is the innermost layer of the Earth?",
    "Option1": "Outer Core",
    "Option2": "Inner Core",
    "Option3": "Mantle",
    "Option4": "Crust",
    "Answer": "Inner Core"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 19,
    "Question": "What type of rock is formed when existing rocks are subjected to heat, pressure, or chemical alteration?",
    "Option1": "Igneous",
    "Option2": "Sedimentary",
    "Option3": "Metamorphic",
    "Option4": "Volcanic",
    "Answer": "Metamorphic"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 20,
    "Question": "What is the name of the large-scale ocean currents that transfer heat around the globe?",
    "Option1": "Tides",
    "Option2": "Waves",
    "Option3": "Ocean conveyor belt",
    "Option4": "Rip currents",
    "Answer": "Ocean conveyor belt"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 21,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of weather and atmospheric phenomena?",
    "Option1": "Climatology",
    "Option2": "Hydrology",
    "Option3": "Meteorology",
    "Option4": "Geophysics",
    "Answer": "Meteorology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 22,
    "Question": "What is the natural phenomenon that occurs when a river overflows its banks?",
    "Option1": "Drought",
    "Option2": "Flood",
    "Option3": "Tornado",
    "Option4": "Earthquake",
    "Answer": "Flood"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 23,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water seeps into cracks in rocks, freezes, and expands, causing the rock to break apart?",
    "Option1": "Chemical weathering",
    "Option2": "Abrasion",
    "Option3": "Frost wedging",
    "Option4": "Exfoliation",
    "Answer": "Frost wedging"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 24,
    "Question": "What is the name of the long, narrow depression in the ocean floor, typically found along tectonic plate boundaries?",
    "Option1": "Mid-ocean ridge",
    "Option2": "Continental shelf",
    "Option3": "Oceanic trench",
    "Option4": "Abyssal plain",
    "Answer": "Oceanic trench"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 25,
    "Question": "What is the layer of the Earth composed primarily of iron and nickel, responsible for generating the Earth's magnetic field?",
    "Option1": "Crust",
    "Option2": "Mantle",
    "Option3": "Outer Core",
    "Option4": "Inner Core",
    "Answer": "Outer Core"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 26,
    "Question": "What is the term for the uppermost part of the mantle, characterized by its plasticity and ability to flow?",
    "Option1": "Lithosphere",
    "Option2": "Asthenosphere",
    "Option3": "Mesosphere",
    "Option4": "Outer core",
    "Answer": "Asthenosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 27,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process by which sediments are compacted and cemented together to form sedimentary rock?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Weathering",
    "Option3": "Lithification",
    "Option4": "Metamorphism",
    "Answer": "Lithification"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 28,
    "Question": "What is the primary factor that determines the Earth's climate zones?",
    "Option1": "Altitude",
    "Option2": "Distance from oceans",
    "Option3": "Latitude",
    "Option4": "Vegetation",
    "Answer": "Latitude"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 29,
    "Question": "What is the name of the largest desert in the world?",
    "Option1": "Sahara Desert",
    "Option2": "Gobi Desert",
    "Option3": "Arabian Desert",
    "Option4": "Antarctic Polar Desert",
    "Answer": "Antarctic Polar Desert"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 30,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long-term change in the Earth's climate?",
    "Option1": "Weather anomaly",
    "Option2": "Climate variability",
    "Option3": "Climate change",
    "Option4": "Atmospheric oscillation",
    "Answer": "Climate change"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 31,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where tectonic plates move apart, creating new crust?",
    "Option1": "Subduction",
    "Option2": "Collision",
    "Option3": "Seafloor spreading",
    "Option4": "Transform faulting",
    "Answer": "Seafloor spreading"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 32,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of oceans and their phenomena?",
    "Option1": "Limnology",
    "Option2": "Hydrology",
    "Option3": "Oceanography",
    "Option4": "Glaciology",
    "Answer": "Oceanography"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 33,
    "Question": "What is the name of the layer of the atmosphere that contains the ozone layer?",
    "Option1": "Troposphere",
    "Option2": "Stratosphere",
    "Option3": "Mesosphere",
    "Option4": "Thermosphere",
    "Answer": "Stratosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 34,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where water from the Earth's surface evaporates and returns to the atmosphere?",
    "Option1": "Condensation",
    "Option2": "Precipitation",
    "Option3": "Evaporation",
    "Option4": "Runoff",
    "Answer": "Evaporation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 35,
    "Question": "What is the name of the line of longitude that passes through Greenwich, England, and is used as the reference point for time zones?",
    "Option1": "Equator",
    "Option2": "International Date Line",
    "Option3": "Prime Meridian",
    "Option4": "Tropic of Capricorn",
    "Answer": "Prime Meridian"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 36,
    "Question": "What is the name of the large crack or fracture in the Earth's crust along which movement has occurred?",
    "Option1": "Fold",
    "Option2": "Fault",
    "Option3": "Ridge",
    "Option4": "Valley",
    "Answer": "Fault"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 37,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's water, including its distribution, movement, and properties?",
    "Option1": "Oceanography",
    "Option2": "Meteorology",
    "Option3": "Hydrology",
    "Option4": "Glaciology",
    "Answer": "Hydrology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 38,
    "Question": "What is the name of the phenomenon where warm, moist air rises and cools, leading to cloud formation and precipitation?",
    "Option1": "Atmospheric pressure",
    "Option2": "Convection",
    "Option3": "Radiation",
    "Option4": "Conduction",
    "Answer": "Convection"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 39,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where groundwater slowly dissolves soluble rock, leading to the formation of caves?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Deposition",
    "Option3": "Chemical weathering",
    "Option4": "Mechanical weathering",
    "Answer": "Chemical weathering"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 40,
    "Question": "What is the term for the sudden release of energy that causes an earthquake?",
    "Option1": "Epicenter",
    "Option2": "Focus",
    "Option3": "Seismic waves",
    "Option4": "Fault rupture",
    "Answer": "Fault rupture"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 41,
    "Question": "What is the name of the layer of the Earth's atmosphere that is furthest from the surface?",
    "Option1": "Troposphere",
    "Option2": "Stratosphere",
    "Option3": "Mesosphere",
    "Option4": "Exosphere",
    "Answer": "Exosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 42,
    "Question": "What is the primary natural process that creates deserts?",
    "Option1": "High rainfall",
    "Option2": "Low temperatures",
    "Option3": "Low precipitation and high evaporation rates",
    "Option4": "Volcanic activity",
    "Answer": "Low precipitation and high evaporation rates"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 43,
    "Question": "What is the name of the instrument used to measure the intensity of an earthquake?",
    "Option1": "Barometer",
    "Option2": "Anemometer",
    "Option3": "Seismograph",
    "Option4": "Thermometer",
    "Answer": "Seismograph"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 44,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where tectonic plates slide past each other horizontally?",
    "Option1": "Convergent boundary",
    "Option2": "Divergent boundary",
    "Option3": "Transform boundary",
    "Option4": "Subduction zone",
    "Answer": "Transform boundary"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 45,
    "Question": "What is the name of the gas in the atmosphere that absorbs most of the Sun's harmful ultraviolet (UV) radiation?",
    "Option1": "Carbon dioxide",
    "Option2": "Nitrogen",
    "Option3": "Oxygen",
    "Option4": "Ozone",
    "Answer": "Ozone"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 46,
    "Question": "What is the term for a large mass of ice that moves slowly over land?",
    "Option1": "Iceberg",
    "Option2": "Glacier",
    "Option3": "Ice sheet",
    "Option4": "Snowdrift",
    "Answer": "Glacier"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 47,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process by which soil and rock are transported by wind?",
    "Option1": "Water erosion",
    "Option2": "Glacial erosion",
    "Option3": "Wind erosion",
    "Option4": "Gravity erosion",
    "Answer": "Wind erosion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 48,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's landforms and the processes that create them?",
    "Option1": "Cartography",
    "Option2": "Geomorphology",
    "Option3": "Topography",
    "Option4": "Pedology",
    "Answer": "Geomorphology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 49,
    "Question": "What is the name of the continuous movement of water on, above, and below the surface of the Earth?",
    "Option1": "Carbon cycle",
    "Option2": "Nitrogen cycle",
    "Option3": "Water cycle (Hydrologic cycle)",
    "Option4": "Rock cycle",
    "Answer": "Water cycle (Hydrologic cycle)"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 50,
    "Question": "What is the term for the point on the Earth's surface directly above the focus of an earthquake?",
    "Option1": "Hypocenter",
    "Option2": "Epicenter",
    "Option3": "Seismic station",
    "Option4": "Fault line",
    "Answer": "Epicenter"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 51,
    "Question": "What is the name of the longest mountain range in the world?",
    "Option1": "Himalayas",
    "Option2": "Andes",
    "Option3": "Rocky Mountains",
    "Option4": "Great Dividing Range",
    "Answer": "Andes"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 52,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where one tectonic plate slides beneath another?",
    "Option1": "Divergence",
    "Option2": "Collision",
    "Option3": "Subduction",
    "Option4": "Spreading",
    "Answer": "Subduction"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 53,
    "Question": "What is the name of the layer of the Earth's atmosphere that is characterized by very high temperatures due to the absorption of solar radiation?",
    "Option1": "Stratosphere",
    "Option2": "Mesosphere",
    "Option3": "Thermosphere",
    "Option4": "Troposphere",
    "Answer": "Thermosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 54,
    "Question": "What is the primary driving force behind the movement of tectonic plates?",
    "Option1": "Solar energy",
    "Option2": "Gravity",
    "Option3": "Convection currents in the mantle",
    "Option4": "Earth's rotation",
    "Answer": "Convection currents in the mantle"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 55,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water, once evaporated, forms clouds and then falls back to Earth as rain, snow, or hail?",
    "Option1": "Condensation",
    "Option2": "Transpiration",
    "Option3": "Precipitation",
    "Option4": "Runoff",
    "Answer": "Precipitation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 56,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's internal structure and seismic waves?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Seismology",
    "Option4": "Volcanology",
    "Answer": "Seismology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 57,
    "Question": "What is the name of the long, narrow chain of underwater mountains that runs through the world's oceans?",
    "Option1": "Oceanic trench",
    "Option2": "Continental slope",
    "Option3": "Mid-ocean ridge",
    "Option4": "Abyssal plain",
    "Answer": "Mid-ocean ridge"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 58,
    "Question": "What is the term for a violent, rotating column of air that extends from a thunderstorm to the ground?",
    "Option1": "Hurricane",
    "Option2": "Typhoon",
    "Option3": "Tornado",
    "Option4": "Blizzard",
    "Answer": "Tornado"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 59,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where sediments are laid down by water, wind, or ice?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Weathering",
    "Option3": "Deposition",
    "Option4": "Compaction",
    "Answer": "Deposition"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 60,
    "Question": "What is the name of the thin, rocky outer layer of the Earth?",
    "Option1": "Mantle",
    "Option2": "Outer Core",
    "Option3": "Crust",
    "Option4": "Lithosphere",
    "Answer": "Crust"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 61,
    "Question": "What is the name of the large-scale wind patterns that circulate around the Earth, influencing global climate?",
    "Option1": "Local winds",
    "Option2": "Monsoons",
    "Option3": "Prevailing winds",
    "Option4": "Trade winds",
    "Answer": "Prevailing winds"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 62,
    "Question": "What is the term for the scientific theory that describes the large-scale motion of Earth's lithosphere?",
    "Option1": "Continental drift",
    "Option2": "Plate tectonics",
    "Option3": "Seafloor spreading",
    "Option4": "Isostasy",
    "Answer": "Plate tectonics"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 63,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where rocks are physically broken down by forces like temperature changes, frost, and abrasion?",
    "Option1": "Chemical weathering",
    "Option2": "Mechanical weathering",
    "Option3": "Dissolution",
    "Option4": "Oxidation",
    "Answer": "Mechanical weathering"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 64,
    "Question": "What is the term for the area where two tectonic plates are moving towards each other?",
    "Option1": "Divergent boundary",
    "Option2": "Transform boundary",
    "Option3": "Convergent boundary",
    "Option4": "Spreading center",
    "Answer": "Convergent boundary"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 65,
    "Question": "What is the name of the Earth's protective layer that filters out most of the harmful solar radiation?",
    "Option1": "Troposphere",
    "Option2": "Stratosphere",
    "Option3": "Ozone layer",
    "Option4": "Ionosphere",
    "Answer": "Ozone layer"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 66,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of past climates based on evidence from ice cores, tree rings, and sediments?",
    "Option1": "Meteorology",
    "Option2": "Paleontology",
    "Option3": "Climatology",
    "Option4": "Paleoclimatology",
    "Answer": "Paleoclimatology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 67,
    "Question": "What is the name of the molten rock beneath the Earth's surface?",
    "Option1": "Lava",
    "Option2": "Ash",
    "Option3": "Magma",
    "Option4": "Pumice",
    "Answer": "Magma"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 68,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a river deposits sediment at its mouth, forming a triangular landform?",
    "Option1": "Canyon",
    "Option2": "Delta",
    "Option3": "Estuary",
    "Option4": "Floodplain",
    "Answer": "Delta"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 69,
    "Question": "What is the name of the type of energy that drives weather and climate on Earth?",
    "Option1": "Geothermal energy",
    "Option2": "Tidal energy",
    "Option3": "Solar energy",
    "Option4": "Nuclear energy",
    "Answer": "Solar energy"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 70,
    "Question": "What is the term for the sudden displacement of a large volume of water, typically caused by an underwater earthquake or volcanic eruption?",
    "Option1": "Storm surge",
    "Option2": "Tidal wave",
    "Option3": "Tsunami",
    "Option4": "Rogue wave",
    "Answer": "Tsunami"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 71,
    "Question": "What is the name of the layer of the Earth that is mostly solid but behaves like a very viscous fluid over long periods?",
    "Option1": "Crust",
    "Option2": "Outer Core",
    "Option3": "Inner Core",
    "Option4": "Mantle",
    "Answer": "Mantle"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 72,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where carbon moves between the atmosphere, oceans, land, and living organisms?",
    "Option1": "Water cycle",
    "Option2": "Nitrogen cycle",
    "Option3": "Carbon cycle",
    "Option4": "Rock cycle",
    "Answer": "Carbon cycle"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 73,
    "Question": "What is the name of the instrument used to measure air pressure?",
    "Option1": "Thermometer",
    "Option2": "Anemometer",
    "Option3": "Barometer",
    "Option4": "Hygrometer",
    "Answer": "Barometer"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 74,
    "Question": "What is the term for the cracking and peeling of outer layers of rock due to changes in temperature?",
    "Option1": "Abrasion",
    "Option2": "Exfoliation",
    "Option3": "Hydrolysis",
    "Option4": "Oxidation",
    "Answer": "Exfoliation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 75,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scientific study of the Earth's resources, including minerals, energy, and water?",
    "Option1": "Environmental science",
    "Option2": "Resource management",
    "Option3": "Economic geology",
    "Option4": "Applied geology",
    "Answer": "Economic geology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 76,
    "Question": "What is the term for the total amount of water on Earth?",
    "Option1": "Atmospheric water",
    "Option2": "Surface water",
    "Option3": "Global water budget",
    "Option4": "Hydrosphere",
    "Answer": "Hydrosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 77,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water that falls as precipitation flows over the land surface?",
    "Option1": "Infiltration",
    "Option2": "Percolation",
    "Option3": "Runoff",
    "Option4": "Evapotranspiration",
    "Answer": "Runoff"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 78,
    "Question": "What is the term for a natural disaster characterized by prolonged periods of unusually low precipitation?",
    "Option1": "Flood",
    "Option2": "Drought",
    "Option3": "Heatwave",
    "Option4": "Blizzard",
    "Answer": "Drought"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 79,
    "Question": "What is the name of the boundary between the Earth's crust and the mantle?",
    "Option1": "Gutenberg discontinuity",
    "Option2": "Lehmann discontinuity",
    "Option3": "Mohorovicic discontinuity (Moho)",
    "Option4": "Conrad discontinuity",
    "Answer": "Mohorovicic discontinuity (Moho)"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 80,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where wind picks up and transports loose sediment, often forming sand dunes?",
    "Option1": "Abrasion",
    "Option2": "Deflation",
    "Option3": "Saltation",
    "Option4": "Suspension",
    "Answer": "Deflation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 81,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scientific study of glaciers and ice sheets?",
    "Option1": "Hydrology",
    "Option2": "Oceanography",
    "Option3": "Glaciology",
    "Option4": "Cryology",
    "Answer": "Glaciology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 82,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a river carves a deep, narrow valley through rock?",
    "Option1": "Delta formation",
    "Option2": "Meander formation",
    "Option3": "Canyon formation",
    "Option4": "Floodplain development",
    "Answer": "Canyon formation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 83,
    "Question": "What is the name of the atmospheric phenomenon characterized by strong winds, heavy precipitation, and often lightning and thunder?",
    "Option1": "Fog",
    "Option2": "Blizzard",
    "Option3": "Thunderstorm",
    "Option4": "Heatwave",
    "Answer": "Thunderstorm"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 84,
    "Question": "What is the term for the total mass of living organisms in a given area or volume?",
    "Option1": "Ecosystem",
    "Option2": "Biodiversity",
    "Option3": "Biomass",
    "Option4": "Habitat",
    "Answer": "Biomass"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 85,
    "Question": "What is the name of the outermost solid layer of the Earth, consisting of the crust and the uppermost mantle?",
    "Option1": "Asthenosphere",
    "Option2": "Mesosphere",
    "Option3": "Lithosphere",
    "Option4": "Outer Core",
    "Answer": "Lithosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 86,
    "Question": "What is the term for the circular motion of ocean water caused by differences in temperature and salinity?",
    "Option1": "Tides",
    "Option2": "Waves",
    "Option3": "Convection currents",
    "Option4": "Ocean gyres",
    "Answer": "Ocean gyres"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 87,
    "Question": "What is the name of the boundary where two tectonic plates move away from each other?",
    "Option1": "Convergent boundary",
    "Option2": "Transform boundary",
    "Option3": "Divergent boundary",
    "Option4": "Subduction zone",
    "Answer": "Divergent boundary"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 88,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's surface features and their distribution?",
    "Option1": "Climatology",
    "Option2": "Cartography",
    "Option3": "Physical geography",
    "Option4": "Demography",
    "Answer": "Physical geography"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 89,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where sediments are compressed by the weight of overlying layers?",
    "Option1": "Cementation",
    "Option2": "Compaction",
    "Option3": "Lithification",
    "Option4": "Deposition",
    "Answer": "Compaction"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 90,
    "Question": "What is the term for the layer of the Earth's atmosphere above the troposphere, extending to about 50 km (31 miles) above the surface?",
    "Option1": "Mesosphere",
    "Option2": "Thermosphere",
    "Option3": "Exosphere",
    "Option4": "Stratosphere",
    "Answer": "Stratosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 91,
    "Question": "What is the name of the large-scale atmospheric circulation cells that drive global weather patterns?",
    "Option1": "Hadley cells",
    "Option2": "Ferrel cells",
    "Option3": "Polar cells",
    "Option4": "All of the above",
    "Answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 92,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where rocks are chemically changed by reactions with water, oxygen, or acids?",
    "Option1": "Mechanical weathering",
    "Option2": "Abrasion",
    "Option3": "Chemical weathering",
    "Option4": "Exfoliation",
    "Answer": "Chemical weathering"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 93,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scientific study of the Earth's physical history and the life forms that have inhabited it?",
    "Option1": "Archaeology",
    "Option2": "Anthropology",
    "Option3": "Paleontology",
    "Option4": "Geochronology",
    "Answer": "Paleontology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 94,
    "Question": "What is the term for the movement of Earth's crust caused by convection currents in the mantle?",
    "Option1": "Continental drift",
    "Option2": "Plate tectonics",
    "Option3": "Isostasy",
    "Option4": "Diastrophism",
    "Answer": "Plate tectonics"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 95,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scale used to measure the magnitude of earthquakes?",
    "Option1": "Beaufort scale",
    "Option2": "Fahrenheit scale",
    "Option3": "Richter scale",
    "Option4": "Mercalli scale",
    "Answer": "Richter scale"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 96,
    "Question": "What is the term for a broad, dome-shaped volcano with gentle slopes, formed by the eruption of fluid basaltic lava?",
    "Option1": "Stratovolcano",
    "Option2": "Cinder cone",
    "Option3": "Shield volcano",
    "Option4": "Caldera",
    "Answer": "Shield volcano"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 97,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water is absorbed by soil and rock?",
    "Option1": "Runoff",
    "Option2": "Evaporation",
    "Option3": "Infiltration",
    "Option4": "Transpiration",
    "Answer": "Infiltration"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 98,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's gravitational field?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Gravimetry",
    "Option4": "Seismology",
    "Answer": "Gravimetry"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 99,
    "Question": "What is the name of the natural process where land slides down a slope due to gravity?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Deposition",
    "Option3": "Landslide",
    "Option4": "Subsidence",
    "Answer": "Landslide"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 100,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where water vapor is released into the atmosphere by plants?",
    "Option1": "Evaporation",
    "Option2": "Condensation",
    "Option3": "Transpiration",
    "Option4": "Precipitation",
    "Answer": "Transpiration"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 101,
    "Question": "What is the name of the layer of the Earth's atmosphere where meteors burn up?",
    "Option1": "Stratosphere",
    "Option2": "Mesosphere",
    "Option3": "Thermosphere",
    "Option4": "Exosphere",
    "Answer": "Mesosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 102,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of ancient life, including fossils?",
    "Option1": "Archaeology",
    "Option2": "Paleontology",
    "Option3": "Anthropology",
    "Option4": "Geochronology",
    "Answer": "Paleontology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 103,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, narrow body of water that extends into the land, often formed by glacial erosion?",
    "Option1": "Delta",
    "Option2": "Estuary",
    "Option3": "Fjord",
    "Option4": "Lagoon",
    "Answer": "Fjord"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 104,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where molten rock solidifies underground, forming intrusive igneous rocks?",
    "Option1": "Extrusion",
    "Option2": "Intrusion",
    "Option3": "Volcanism",
    "Option4": "Crystallization",
    "Answer": "Intrusion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 105,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a river deposits sediment along its banks, forming a flat, fertile area?",
    "Option1": "Canyon",
    "Option2": "Delta",
    "Option3": "Floodplain",
    "Option4": "Meander",
    "Answer": "Floodplain"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 106,
    "Question": "What is the name of the type of plate boundary where crust is neither created nor destroyed, but plates slide past each other?",
    "Option1": "Convergent",
    "Option2": "Divergent",
    "Option3": "Transform",
    "Option4": "Subduction",
    "Answer": "Transform"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 107,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's crust and its deformation?",
    "Option1": "Geomorphology",
    "Option2": "Tectonics",
    "Option3": "Structural geology",
    "Option4": "Sedimentology",
    "Answer": "Structural geology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 108,
    "Question": "What is the name of the outermost layer of the Earth that is liquid and composed mainly of iron and nickel?",
    "Option1": "Inner Core",
    "Option2": "Outer Core",
    "Option3": "Mantle",
    "Option4": "Crust",
    "Answer": "Outer Core"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 109,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where water enters the ground and moves downward through the soil and rock layers?",
    "Option1": "Runoff",
    "Option2": "Evaporation",
    "Option3": "Percolation",
    "Option4": "Transpiration",
    "Answer": "Percolation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 110,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scientific study of the Earth's atmosphere and its phenomena?",
    "Option1": "Climatology",
    "Option2": "Meteorology",
    "Option3": "Aeronomy",
    "Option4": "Atmospheric science",
    "Answer": "Atmospheric science"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 111,
    "Question": "What is the term for a circular depression at the summit of a volcano, often formed after an eruption?",
    "Option1": "Vent",
    "Option2": "Crater",
    "Option3": "Caldera",
    "Option4": "Fissure",
    "Answer": "Caldera"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 112,
    "Question": "What is the name of the geological process where rocks are bent or folded due to compressive forces?",
    "Option1": "Faulting",
    "Option2": "Folding",
    "Option3": "Erosion",
    "Option4": "Weathering",
    "Answer": "Folding"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 113,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the distribution of water on Earth, including rivers, lakes, and groundwater?",
    "Option1": "Oceanography",
    "Option2": "Limnology",
    "Option3": "Hydrology",
    "Option4": "Glaciology",
    "Answer": "Hydrology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 114,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where water flows over land and picks up sediment, carrying it to a new location?",
    "Option1": "Deposition",
    "Option2": "Weathering",
    "Option3": "Erosion",
    "Option4": "Infiltration",
    "Answer": "Erosion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 115,
    "Question": "What is the name of the boundary between the Earth's mantle and the outer core?",
    "Option1": "Mohorovicic discontinuity",
    "Option2": "Lehmann discontinuity",
    "Option3": "Gutenberg discontinuity",
    "Option4": "Conrad discontinuity",
    "Answer": "Gutenberg discontinuity"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 116,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's past, including its geological history and the evolution of life?",
    "Option1": "Archaeology",
    "Option2": "Anthropology",
    "Option3": "Historical geology",
    "Option4": "Geochronology",
    "Answer": "Historical geology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 117,
    "Question": "What is the term for the movement of Earth's crustal plates, resulting in earthquakes, volcanic activity, and mountain building?",
    "Option1": "Continental drift",
    "Option2": "Plate tectonics",
    "Option3": "Isostasy",
    "Option4": "Diastrophism",
    "Answer": "Plate tectonics"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 118,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process by which rocks and minerals are broken down by the action of living organisms?",
    "Option1": "Mechanical weathering",
    "Option2": "Chemical weathering",
    "Option3": "Biological weathering",
    "Option4": "Frost wedging",
    "Answer": "Biological weathering"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 119,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, narrow valley formed by the pulling apart of the Earth's crust?",
    "Option1": "Canyon",
    "Option2": "Rift valley",
    "Option3": "Graben",
    "Option4": "Horst",
    "Answer": "Rift valley"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 120,
    "Question": "What is the name of the largest known earthquake in recorded history?",
    "Option1": "1906 San Francisco earthquake",
    "Option2": "1960 Valdivia earthquake",
    "Option3": "2004 Indian Ocean earthquake and tsunami",
    "Option4": "1964 Alaska earthquake",
    "Answer": "1960 Valdivia earthquake"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 121,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's landforms and the processes that create and change them?",
    "Option1": "Cartography",
    "Option2": "Topography",
    "Option3": "Geomorphology",
    "Option4": "Pedology",
    "Answer": "Geomorphology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 122,
    "Question": "What is the term for the release of gases and other materials from a volcano?",
    "Option1": "Lava flow",
    "Option2": "Pyroclastic flow",
    "Option3": "Volcanic eruption",
    "Option4": "Ashfall",
    "Answer": "Volcanic eruption"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 123,
    "Question": "What is the name of the continuous process by which rocks are formed, altered, destroyed, and reformed?",
    "Option1": "Water cycle",
    "Option2": "Carbon cycle",
    "Option3": "Rock cycle",
    "Option4": "Nitrogen cycle",
    "Answer": "Rock cycle"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 124,
    "Question": "What is the term for the scientific study of the Earth's surface and the mapping of its features?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Cartography",
    "Option4": "Topography",
    "Answer": "Cartography"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 125,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water vapor freezes directly into ice, such as frost or snow?",
    "Option1": "Condensation",
    "Option2": "Deposition",
    "Option3": "Sublimation",
    "Option4": "Freezing",
    "Answer": "Deposition"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 126,
    "Question": "What is the term for the large-scale subsidence of a land surface due to the removal of underlying support?",
    "Option1": "Landslide",
    "Option2": "Erosion",
    "Option3": "Subsidence",
    "Option4": "Compaction",
    "Answer": "Subsidence"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 127,
    "Question": "What is the name of the type of cloud that appears as thin, wispy strands, high in the atmosphere?",
    "Option1": "Cumulus",
    "Option2": "Stratus",
    "Option3": "Cirrus",
    "Option4": "Nimbus",
    "Answer": "Cirrus"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 128,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of earthquakes and seismic waves?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Seismology",
    "Option4": "Volcanology",
    "Answer": "Seismology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 129,
    "Question": "What is the term for the amount of water vapor in the air?",
    "Option1": "Temperature",
    "Option2": "Pressure",
    "Option3": "Humidity",
    "Option4": "Wind speed",
    "Answer": "Humidity"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 130,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scientific study of the Earth's physical properties, such as its magnetic field, gravity, and heat flow?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Geochemistry",
    "Option4": "Geodesy",
    "Answer": "Geophysics"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 131,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, narrow ridge formed by the deposition of sediment by a glacier?",
    "Option1": "Drumlin",
    "Option2": "Esker",
    "Option3": "Moraine",
    "Option4": "Kame",
    "Answer": "Moraine"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 132,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where rocks are broken down by the force of moving water, ice, or wind?",
    "Option1": "Chemical weathering",
    "Option2": "Mechanical weathering",
    "Option3": "Abrasion",
    "Option4": "Dissolution",
    "Answer": "Abrasion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 133,
    "Question": "What is the term for the scientific study of the Earth's past climates?",
    "Option1": "Meteorology",
    "Option2": "Climatology",
    "Option3": "Paleoclimatology",
    "Option4": "Historical climatology",
    "Answer": "Paleoclimatology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 134,
    "Question": "What is the name of the type of rock that contains fossils?",
    "Option1": "Igneous",
    "Option2": "Metamorphic",
    "Option3": "Sedimentary",
    "Option4": "Volcanic",
    "Answer": "Sedimentary"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 135,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where carbon dioxide from the atmosphere dissolves in ocean water, making it more acidic?",
    "Option1": "Ocean warming",
    "Option2": "Ocean acidification",
    "Option3": "Carbon sequestration",
    "Option4": "Coral bleaching",
    "Answer": "Ocean acidification"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 136,
    "Question": "What is the name of the layer of the Earth that is solid and composed mainly of iron and nickel, despite being at extremely high temperatures?",
    "Option1": "Outer Core",
    "Option2": "Inner Core",
    "Option3": "Mantle",
    "Option4": "Crust",
    "Answer": "Inner Core"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 137,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's magnetic field and its variations?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Geomagnetism",
    "Option4": "Paleomagnetism",
    "Answer": "Geomagnetism"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 138,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a river curves and winds across a flat floodplain?",
    "Option1": "Canyon formation",
    "Option2": "Delta formation",
    "Option3": "Meandering",
    "Option4": "Braiding",
    "Answer": "Meandering"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 139,
    "Question": "What is the name of the instrument used to measure wind speed?",
    "Option1": "Barometer",
    "Option2": "Thermometer",
    "Option3": "Anemometer",
    "Option4": "Hygrometer",
    "Answer": "Anemometer"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 140,
    "Question": "What is the term for a large body of air with similar temperature and humidity characteristics?",
    "Option1": "Front",
    "Option2": "Cyclone",
    "Option3": "Air mass",
    "Option4": "Anticyclone",
    "Answer": "Air mass"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 141,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's internal heat and its effects?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Geothermics",
    "Option4": "Volcanology",
    "Answer": "Geothermics"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 142,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water, once frozen in glaciers, melts and flows into rivers and oceans?",
    "Option1": "Evaporation",
    "Option2": "Condensation",
    "Option3": "Meltwater runoff",
    "Option4": "Sublimation",
    "Answer": "Meltwater runoff"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 143,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where molten rock reaches the Earth's surface and erupts from a volcano?",
    "Option1": "Intrusion",
    "Option2": "Extrusion",
    "Option3": "Metamorphism",
    "Option4": "Lithification",
    "Answer": "Extrusion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 144,
    "Question": "What is the name of the boundary between two air masses with different temperatures and densities?",
    "Option1": "Jet stream",
    "Option2": "Front",
    "Option3": "Cyclone",
    "Option4": "Anticyclone",
    "Answer": "Front"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 145,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, continuous crack on the ocean floor where new oceanic crust is formed?",
    "Option1": "Oceanic trench",
    "Option2": "Mid-ocean ridge",
    "Option3": "Subduction zone",
    "Option4": "Transform fault",
    "Answer": "Mid-ocean ridge"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 146,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of rocks?",
    "Option1": "Mineralogy",
    "Option2": "Petrology",
    "Option3": "Geochemistry",
    "Option4": "Stratigraphy",
    "Answer": "Petrology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 147,
    "Question": "What is the name of the phenomenon where the Earth's magnetic poles periodically reverse their positions?",
    "Option1": "Magnetic storm",
    "Option2": "Geomagnetic reversal",
    "Option3": "Magnetic anomaly",
    "Option4": "Polar wander",
    "Answer": "Geomagnetic reversal"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 148,
    "Question": "What is the term for a large, rapidly moving flow of hot gases, ash, and volcanic debris that can be extremely destructive?",
    "Option1": "Lava flow",
    "Option2": "Mudflow",
    "Option3": "Pyroclastic flow",
    "Option4": "Ashfall",
    "Answer": "Pyroclastic flow"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 149,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scientific study of the Earth's surface and the processes that shape it?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geomorphology",
    "Option3": "Topography",
    "Option4": "Physical geography",
    "Answer": "Geomorphology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 150,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where water vapor from the atmosphere condenses directly onto a cold surface, forming ice crystals?",
    "Option1": "Dew",
    "Option2": "Frost",
    "Option3": "Fog",
    "Option4": "Hail",
    "Answer": "Frost"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 151,
    "Question": "What is the name of the geological process where sediments are naturally glued together by minerals?",
    "Option1": "Compaction",
    "Option2": "Lithification",
    "Option3": "Cementation",
    "Option4": "Deposition",
    "Answer": "Cementation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 152,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's crustal movements and deformations?",
    "Option1": "Geophysics",
    "Option2": "Tectonics",
    "Option3": "Structural geology",
    "Option4": "Geodesy",
    "Answer": "Tectonics"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 153,
    "Question": "What is the term for the gradual movement of continents across the Earth's surface over geological time?",
    "Option1": "Plate tectonics",
    "Option2": "Continental drift",
    "Option3": "Seafloor spreading",
    "Option4": "Isostasy",
    "Answer": "Continental drift"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 154,
    "Question": "What is the name of the phenomenon where hot water and steam erupt from the Earth's surface?",
    "Option1": "Hot spring",
    "Option2": "Geyser",
    "Option3": "Fumarole",
    "Option4": "Mud pot",
    "Answer": "Geyser"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 155,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of minerals?",
    "Option1": "Petrology",
    "Option2": "Crystallography",
    "Option3": "Mineralogy",
    "Option4": "Geochemistry",
    "Answer": "Mineralogy"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 156,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long-period sea wave caused by a massive displacement of water, often from underwater earthquakes?",
    "Option1": "Storm surge",
    "Option2": "Tidal wave",
    "Option3": "Tsunami",
    "Option4": "Rogue wave",
    "Answer": "Tsunami"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 157,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where sediments are carried away by water, wind, or ice and deposited elsewhere?",
    "Option1": "Weathering",
    "Option2": "Erosion",
    "Option3": "Transportation",
    "Option4": "Deposition",
    "Answer": "Transportation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 158,
    "Question": "What is the term for the scientific study of the Earth's landforms and the processes that create them?",
    "Option1": "Cartography",
    "Option2": "Topography",
    "Option3": "Geomorphology",
    "Option4": "Physical geography",
    "Answer": "Geomorphology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 159,
    "Question": "What is the name of the outermost solid layer of the Earth, consisting of the crust and a portion of the upper mantle?",
    "Option1": "Asthenosphere",
    "Option2": "Mesosphere",
    "Option3": "Lithosphere",
    "Option4": "Outer Core",
    "Answer": "Lithosphere"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 160,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, narrow depression in the Earth's surface formed by the downward movement of a block of crust between two faults?",
    "Option1": "Horst",
    "Option2": "Graben",
    "Option3": "Anticline",
    "Option4": "Syncline",
    "Answer": "Graben"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 161,
    "Question": "What is the name of the type of volcano characterized by steep slopes and explosive eruptions of viscous lava and ash?",
    "Option1": "Shield volcano",
    "Option2": "Cinder cone",
    "Option3": "Stratovolcano (composite volcano)",
    "Option4": "Dome volcano",
    "Answer": "Stratovolcano (composite volcano)"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 162,
    "Question": "What is the scientific term for the study of the Earth's atmosphere and its long-term patterns?",
    "Option1": "Meteorology",
    "Option2": "Climatology",
    "Option3": "Aeronomy",
    "Option4": "Atmospheric physics",
    "Answer": "Climatology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 163,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a river deposits sediment at the inside bend of a meander?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Cut bank formation",
    "Option3": "Point bar formation",
    "Option4": "Floodplain development",
    "Answer": "Point bar formation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 164,
    "Question": "What is the name of the phenomenon where ocean currents bring cold, nutrient-rich water from the deep ocean to the surface?",
    "Option1": "Downwelling",
    "Option2": "Upwelling",
    "Option3": "El Niño",
    "Option4": "La Niña",
    "Answer": "Upwelling"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 165,
    "Question": "What is the term for the scientific study of soils, including their formation, classification, and properties?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Agronomy",
    "Option3": "Pedology",
    "Option4": "Soil science",
    "Answer": "Pedology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 166,
    "Question": "What is the name of the Earth's earliest known supercontinent?",
    "Option1": "Pangaea",
    "Option2": "Rodinia",
    "Option3": "Columbia",
    "Option4": "Vaalbara",
    "Answer": "Vaalbara"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 167,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a landform gradually wears away due to natural forces like wind and water?",
    "Option1": "Deposition",
    "Option2": "Accretion",
    "Option3": "Degradation",
    "Option4": "Aggradation",
    "Answer": "Degradation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 168,
    "Question": "What is the name of the boundary between the Earth's inner and outer core?",
    "Option1": "Mohorovicic discontinuity",
    "Option2": "Gutenberg discontinuity",
    "Option3": "Lehmann discontinuity",
    "Option4": "Conrad discontinuity",
    "Answer": "Lehmann discontinuity"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 169,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the history of the Earth and its life forms as revealed by fossils?",
    "Option1": "Archaeology",
    "Option2": "Paleontology",
    "Option3": "Geochronology",
    "Option4": "Stratigraphy",
    "Answer": "Paleontology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 170,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where water, once infiltrated into the ground, moves horizontally through porous rock or soil?",
    "Option1": "Percolation",
    "Option2": "Runoff",
    "Option3": "Subsurface flow",
    "Option4": "Evapotranspiration",
    "Answer": "Subsurface flow"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 171,
    "Question": "What is the name of the type of cloud that forms a continuous, low-lying grey layer, often bringing drizzle or light rain?",
    "Option1": "Cirrus",
    "Option2": "Cumulus",
    "Option3": "Stratus",
    "Option4": "Altocumulus",
    "Answer": "Stratus"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 172,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's physical structure, its history, and the processes that act on it?",
    "Option1": "Geography",
    "Option2": "Geology",
    "Option3": "Meteorology",
    "Option4": "Oceanography",
    "Answer": "Geology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 173,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a river's flow is significantly reduced due to prolonged drought or overuse?",
    "Option1": "Flooding",
    "Option2": "Desiccation",
    "Option3": "Channelization",
    "Option4": "Sedimentation",
    "Answer": "Desiccation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 174,
    "Question": "What is the name of the phenomenon where rising air cools and its water vapor condenses, forming clouds?",
    "Option1": "Evaporation",
    "Option2": "Adiabatic cooling",
    "Option3": "Convection",
    "Option4": "Radiation",
    "Answer": "Adiabatic cooling"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 175,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, narrow body of water that connects two larger bodies of water?",
    "Option1": "Bay",
    "Option2": "Gulf",
    "Option3": "Strait",
    "Option4": "Fjord",
    "Answer": "Strait"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 176,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's natural resources and their management?",
    "Option1": "Environmental science",
    "Option2": "Resource geology",
    "Option3": "Conservation biology",
    "Option4": "Sustainable development",
    "Answer": "Resource geology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 177,
    "Question": "What is the name of the geological process where new rock layers are laid down on top of older ones?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Weathering",
    "Option3": "Stratification",
    "Option4": "Folding",
    "Answer": "Stratification"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 178,
    "Question": "What is the term for the scientific study of the Earth's magnetic field, including its origin and variations?",
    "Option1": "Geophysics",
    "Option2": "Geomagnetism",
    "Option3": "Paleomagnetism",
    "Option4": "Electromagnetism",
    "Answer": "Geomagnetism"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 179,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where a volcano erupts with a relatively gentle, effusive flow of low-viscosity lava?",
    "Option1": "Explosive eruption",
    "Option2": "Effusive eruption",
    "Option3": "Phreatic eruption",
    "Option4": "Plinian eruption",
    "Answer": "Effusive eruption"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 180,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where seawater is heated by magma and rises through cracks in the seafloor, forming hydrothermal vents?",
    "Option1": "Oceanic circulation",
    "Option2": "Hydrothermal activity",
    "Option3": "Volcanism",
    "Option4": "Seafloor spreading",
    "Answer": "Hydrothermal activity"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 181,
    "Question": "What is the name of the scientific study of the Earth's gravitational field and its effect on the Earth's shape?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Geodesy",
    "Option4": "Gravimetry",
    "Answer": "Geodesy"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 182,
    "Question": "What is the term for a large natural elevation of the Earth's surface rising abruptly from the surrounding level?",
    "Option1": "Hill",
    "Option2": "Plateau",
    "Option3": "Mountain",
    "Option4": "Valley",
    "Answer": "Mountain"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 183,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water changes from a liquid to a gas?",
    "Option1": "Condensation",
    "Option2": "Freezing",
    "Option3": "Evaporation",
    "Option4": "Melting",
    "Answer": "Evaporation"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 184,
    "Question": "What is the term for the amount of dissolved salts in water?",
    "Option1": "Density",
    "Option2": "Temperature",
    "Option3": "Salinity",
    "Option4": "Acidity",
    "Answer": "Salinity"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 185,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's landforms and the processes that create them?",
    "Option1": "Topography",
    "Option2": "Cartography",
    "Option3": "Geomorphology",
    "Option4": "Physical geography",
    "Answer": "Geomorphology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 186,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water seeps into the ground and becomes groundwater?",
    "Option1": "Runoff",
    "Option2": "Evaporation",
    "Option3": "Infiltration",
    "Option4": "Transpiration",
    "Answer": "Infiltration"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 187,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, narrow body of land extending out into a body of water?",
    "Option1": "Bay",
    "Option2": "Peninsula",
    "Option3": "Island",
    "Option4": "Isthmus",
    "Answer": "Peninsula"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 188,
    "Question": "What is the name of the type of rock that forms when layers of sediment are compressed and cemented together?",
    "Option1": "Igneous",
    "Option2": "Metamorphic",
    "Option3": "Sedimentary",
    "Option4": "Volcanic",
    "Answer": "Sedimentary"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 189,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's magnetic field in the past?",
    "Option1": "Geomagnetism",
    "Option2": "Geophysics",
    "Option3": "Paleomagnetism",
    "Option4": "Magnetostratigraphy",
    "Answer": "Paleomagnetism"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 190,
    "Question": "What is the term for the movement of water from the Earth's surface into the atmosphere through evaporation and transpiration?",
    "Option1": "Precipitation",
    "Option2": "Condensation",
    "Option3": "Evapotranspiration",
    "Option4": "Runoff",
    "Answer": "Evapotranspiration"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 191,
    "Question": "What is the name of the geological time period during which the dinosaurs lived?",
    "Option1": "Paleozoic Era",
    "Option2": "Mesozoic Era",
    "Option3": "Cenozoic Era",
    "Option4": "Precambrian Era",
    "Answer": "Mesozoic Era"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 192,
    "Question": "What is the term for the process where a river deposits sediment as its flow slows down?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Weathering",
    "Option3": "Deposition",
    "Option4": "Transportation",
    "Answer": "Deposition"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 193,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of ancient environments and their ecosystems?",
    "Option1": "Paleontology",
    "Option2": "Paleoclimatology",
    "Option3": "Paleoecology",
    "Option4": "Geobiology",
    "Answer": "Paleoecology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 194,
    "Question": "What is the name of the natural process where parts of the Earth's crust rise or fall relative to sea level?",
    "Option1": "Erosion",
    "Option2": "Isostasy",
    "Option3": "Subsidence",
    "Option4": "Uplift",
    "Answer": "Isostasy"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 195,
    "Question": "What is the term for a low-lying, swampy area near a coastline, often influenced by tides?",
    "Option1": "Delta",
    "Option2": "Estuary",
    "Option3": "Lagoon",
    "Option4": "Marsh",
    "Answer": "Marsh"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 196,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's water, including its properties, distribution, and circulation?",
    "Option1": "Oceanography",
    "Option2": "Hydrology",
    "Option3": "Limnology",
    "Option4": "Cryology",
    "Answer": "Hydrology"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 197,
    "Question": "What is the name of the geological process where magma intrudes into existing rock layers, forming features like dikes and sills?",
    "Option1": "Extrusion",
    "Option2": "Intrusion",
    "Option3": "Volcanism",
    "Option4": "Metamorphism",
    "Answer": "Intrusion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 198,
    "Question": "What is the term for a crack in the Earth's crust along which there has been significant movement?",
    "Option1": "Fold",
    "Option2": "Joint",
    "Option3": "Fault",
    "Option4": "Fissure",
    "Answer": "Fault"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 199,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's structure, composition, and physical processes?",
    "Option1": "Geography",
    "Option2": "Geology",
    "Option3": "Geophysics",
    "Option4": "Geochemistry",
    "Answer": "Geophysics"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 200,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where water and wind shape the Earth's surface over long periods?",
    "Option1": "Weathering",
    "Option2": "Deposition",
    "Option3": "Erosion",
    "Option4": "Geological shaping",
    "Answer": "Erosion"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 201,
    "Question": "What is the term for a large, long-lasting ice mass that covers a vast area of land?",
    "Option1": "Glacier",
    "Option2": "Iceberg",
    "Option3": "Ice sheet",
    "Option4": "Ice cap",
    "Answer": "Ice sheet"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 202,
    "Question": "What is the name of the natural process where carbon from the atmosphere is stored in rocks, soil, and oceans?",
    "Option1": "Carbon release",
    "Option2": "Carbon sequestration",
    "Option3": "Carbon cycle",
    "Option4": "Carbon emission",
    "Answer": "Carbon sequestration"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 203,
    "Question": "What is the term for a relatively short, sharp increase in ocean water level, often caused by a storm?",
    "Option1": "Tsunami",
    "Option2": "Tidal wave",
    "Option3": "Storm surge",
    "Option4": "Rip current",
    "Answer": "Storm surge"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 204,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of the Earth's land surface and the methods of representing it on maps?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Geography",
    "Option3": "Topography",
    "Option4": "Cartography",
    "Answer": "Topography"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 205,
    "Question": "What is the name of the process where sediments are carried by a river and deposited at its mouth, forming a large, fan-shaped landform?",
    "Option1": "Canyon",
    "Option2": "Delta",
    "Option3": "Estuary",
    "Option4": "Floodplain",
    "Answer": "Delta"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 206,
    "Question": "What is the term for a long, deep, and narrow valley with steep sides, often carved by a river or glacier?",
    "Option1": "Gorge",
    "Option2": "Ravine",
    "Option3": "Canyon",
    "Option4": "Valley",
    "Answer": "Canyon"
  },
  {
    "question_no.": 207,
    "Question": "What is the scientific study of volcanoes and volcanic phenomena?",
    "Option1": "Geology",
    "Option2": "Seismology",
    "Option3": "Volcanology",
    "Option4": "Petrology",
    "Answer": "Volcanology"
  }
]